All right, Sam is away today and uh you
know when the cat's away, the mice will
play. So, I get to indulge in some of my
favorite rabbit holes I go down.
Our guest today is both an entrepreneur.
You've built and sold multiple companies
in the in the video gaming space, which
kind of led you down the the the pathway
of trying to think through are we living
in a simulation? So, let's start there.
what is the theory and then how you kind
of stumbled into believing this.
>> Yeah. So, simulation theory is the idea
that uh the world that we're living in,
the physical world is not really
physical at all. That in fact we are
inside of some type of virtual reality
or a computer program. I I like to say
we're inside a massively multiplayer
video game. The most popular pop culture
reference really is The Matrix. Neo
Kanarie starts off at the beginning
going to work at a computer software
company called Meta Cortex and he thinks
it's a real world and he thinks he has a
real job and it turns out the whole
thing was an elaborate you know virtual
reality of the year 1999 which is of
course when the Matrix came out. So
that's kind of a [clears throat] a very
quick overview.
>> Yeah. And I know it sounds you know
obviously a little bit offthe-wall. I
remember the first time I heard about
it. I think Elon Musk was talking about
it like a decade ago and he says it in
the very Elon matterof-act way where
he's like um you know if you look at the
plot of video games we go from Pong
which is like two lines and a dot on a
screen to where we have you know video
games today that's like a 30 40 year
period which is like the blink of an eye
in uh the time scale of Earth. So 30 40
years we go from two lines in a dot to
like you know Grand Theft Auto type of
type of stuff. And then he said um you
know obviously any sufficiently
technologically advanced civilization
would want to create a simulation cuz
it's way cheaper to find out how things
are going to go in a simulation than it
is to go test things in the real world.
So there's huge incentive. Clearly if
you could you would build it. And so
then there's a question of like is this
the real one and we're going to make a
simulation later or did some you know
was there a real one and this is the
simulation and he his conclusion was
more than likely this is the simulation
and he just sort of said it matter of
fact and then you know they changed
topics and my mind was blown and you
know my brain is scattered on the wall
and I'm trying to figure out what the
hell he's talking about. I started
thinking about it and you know at the
time I would say this was preai when he
was talking about this it sounded like
you know kind of just nerd dream I don't
know it didn't you know it was hard to
really wrap your head around it wasn't
there wasn't a lot where you could sort
of like squinch your eyes and see it
then now let's fast forward we have AI
chat bots AI voice AI imagery I mean you
can't you can't tell if a video is real
or fake anymore like we're we're already
at that cusp the touring test of looking
at a video. My mom can't tell if a video
is real or fake at all. Zero.
>> Yeah. I mean, is my background real or
not at at this point, right? Similarly,
am I really talking to you or not?
Actually, I'm not. I'm talking to my
computer which is transmitting the image
and it's, you know, transmitting it to
your computer and playing it out on your
computer. But Elon said that back in the
year 2016 at the code conference and his
conclusion was that the chances that we
are in base reality
which would mean you're not in a
simulation is uh one in billions. So you
flip that around and say okay what he
was trying to say is the chances that we
are in a simulation is billions to one
or
>> so so what is the history of this like
where did he get it? Was this is this a
popular theory I just hadn't heard
about? You know what's what's the kind
of origin story? Well, the origin story,
what he was referring to is something
called the simulation argument. Now,
what happened was The Matrix came out in
1999. This wasn't the first, you know,
representation of living in a virtual
world, but it it became the most talked
about film of that year. Before that,
you had Philip K. Dick, who's a
well-known science fiction writer behind
uh he wrote the novels behind
Bladeunner, Minority Report, and the
series The Man in the High Castle. In
1977 in Mets France he actually said we
are living in a computer programmed
reality and the only clue we have to it
is when some variable is changed some
alteration occurs in our reality. Even
he wasn't the first to to really you
know present this idea. In the year 1999
there was another film called the 13th
floor which in some ways was a better
representation of the simulation
argument which I'll come to in a second
which was put forth by Nick Bostonramm a
philosopher at Oxford. And that's really
what Elon was referring to. But uh the
13th floor was actually based on a novel
called Similacron 3 which was from the
1960s. So you can see this idea has been
floating around for quite a while. But
what happened was in the early 2000s
philosophers began to take this
seriously. So the Wowskis were who made
the matrix were inspired by the work of
Philip K. Dick. But what happened was
when they did the matrix sequels in 2002
2003 they started bringing in like real
academic philosophers. But that same
year another philosopher named Nick
Bostonramm at argument actually put out
a a paper called are you living in a
computer simulation. And so what
Bostonramm was essentially saying if you
boil it down was that there's three
possibilities. Hey, I got something
pretty cool to share with you guys. So
if you're like me, you listen to
podcasts or YouTube videos and you like
to take notes. You're here to learn and
that's a lot of effort. Sometimes you're
on the go and you can't do it. And so
the folks at HubSpot who are sponsoring
the podcast have done something pretty
cool for you. They have created the MFM
vault. It's a place to go find notes and
resources that they pull from the
different episodes that we do. So if we
have a guest on that shares their
fivepoint framework, they write down
those five points with the examples that
the guest gave and they put the notes
there for you. So if you want to access
the vault, it's totally free. All you
got to do is click the link in the
description below and you can access all
the notes and the stuff in the vault.
We're going to keep adding to this,
trying to make it better over time.
Thank you to HubSpot. This is a very
cool way for them to sponsor the
podcast, but by instead of telling you
to go buy their stuff, they're actually
giving you something instead.
>> One, no civilization can ever create
these simulations. Okay. So then the
chances that we're in a simulation are
basically zero. the the second one which
I kind of fold into together into the
first one but basically said it's
possible but the civilizations that get
there decide not to make any
simulations. Okay. So in that case again
the chance is very low that we'd be
inside a simulation because they aren't
making or you are most likely in a
simulation. And the third option, it
seems like a jump there, but basically
what he's saying is that if they can
create one simulation, they can create
multiple simulations and they can create
a billion simulations. So there's a
billion simulated worlds. There's only
one physical world. Statistically
speaking, which one are you more likely
to be in if, and this is the point, the
leap that I think most people have a
tough time making. If you ever watch
Boston on Joe Rogan, you know, Rogan had
a hard time understanding this. It's if
you can't tell the difference, then you
know what are the chances that you're
inside the simulation? Well, it's at
least 50/50, right? If you can't tell,
>> right?
>> Uh but if there's a billion simulated
worlds and there's only one real world,
then you're basically, you know, the
chances you're in based reality is one
in billions.
>> Okay, so let's [clears throat] let's
simplify. So, uh because I want to kind
of break it down. What what's
interesting about this to me is
obviously there's the mind-blowing comp
part of this, you know, just being
open-minded and saying, "Well, what if,
right? Like, let's just walk down that
road for a second and see where it takes
us." So, that's obviously just like from
a curiosity point of view, you know,
being open-minded person. That's
interesting. The second is the the
people that are saying this. So you
talked about Elon Musk, you talked
about, you know, Bostonramm who's, you
know, at Oxford, you yourself, you're a
computer scientist, you're an
entrepreneur, you're, you know, it's not
like conspiracy theories from the cooks
of the world. You know what I mean? Like
the the people who tend to take this
more seriously tend to be some of the
more serious people that you would take
seriously in the world. And so that's I
think already one fascinating part of
this. The second fascinating part is
that it's not just the computer
scientists that talk about this. So
you've talked about how in religions
there's a lot of references to this, you
know, in ancient texts before there was
ever even a computer.
>> And you know, I've heard you say that in
passing, but I didn't know any spec I
wanted to hear a little more specifics
of what you're referring to when you say
that. Well, you know, the subtitle of my
book is an MIT computer scientist shows
why AI, quantum physics, and eastern
mystics all agree we're in a video game.
And so, there's actually two versions of
simulation theory. Uh, it's the NPC
version or flavor of simulation theory
and the RPG version. So, RPG stands for
role playing game. Now, in the NPC
version, we're all just AI characters
inside a a simulation that's running on
a type of computer. In the RPG version,
the simulation is also running on
computation, but there's a player of the
game who exists outside of the game. And
so it's that version that as I started
to dip into the mystical texts of old
particularly the yogic traditions
particularly Hinduism and Buddhism and
what I found is they all shared certain
ideas and those ideas would have to have
been explained to people back then in a
way that would make sense to them.
Right? So in the uh Buddhist and Hindu
traditions the world is an illusion.
It's a type of maya. I mean the word
maya literally means illusion but it
also means a carefully crafted illusion
of the type that you know you kind of
agree to be a part of almost as if
you're going to uh like a magic show and
you know that guy you know whoever he is
David Copperfield whoever is not really
sawing that woman in half you know it's
an illusion but you're like wow and the
more convincing the illusion the more
interesting the effect and so I found
that this was such a common idea that if
you could map it onto simulation theory,
you find that these ancient texts used
scientific or technological metaphors of
the time in order to make it
interesting. Now, one thing that's
shared and turns out that's actually
that idea is shared in some of the
Abrahamic religions as well. Like it it
literally you know in the Quran it says
you know that this world is a type of
enjoyable delusion. Okay. Elguri matal
which is Arabic for an enjoyable
delusion. Well what does that mean? Well
some people translate it as a sport or a
game. Uh and so they're trying to
express these ideas in ways that make
sense back then. Now in the the Bhagavad
Gita it says that the soul which is
called the atman actually puts on the
body just like the body puts on a set of
clothes. So that's believe it or not
that's a technological metaphor right?
Clothes are a kind of technology and
they're trying to explain something
that's very mysterious. How do you
incarnate and enter into the world? Now
of course in the uh the eastern
traditions you have the reincarnation.
So you also take off those clothes and
then you put on a different set of
clothes and you play a different role.
Now how would you describe that to
somebody today? I would say today you
would describe it probably the best way
to describe it is you put on a virtual
reality headset, you enter this illusory
world, you go through a process of
forgetfulness. Now this is an important
component that exists in every single
culture in the world is trying to
describe this process of forgetfulness.
The Greeks have lee, the river of
forgetfulness. Plato describes how the
soul incarnates by crossing the river of
forgetfulness. The Chinese have mang po,
the goddess of forgetfulness. Even in
the Islamic traditions, they say that
the word for a human in Arabic is insan.
Insan literally means prisoner. You say
prisoner of what? There's another Arabic
word called Nissan, which means
forgetfulness. So you're basically a
prisoner of forgetfulness. So, a better
way to describe it today is you put on
this virtual reality headset and
everything looks so real, you become so
engrossed in what's happening around you
that you forget who you were. You forget
the life selection process that you went
through. If you were if you were
choosing what you're going to play in a
video game, who's choosing like Walmart
Middle Manager, you know what I mean?
like [laughter]
and I can see why people choose that in
in kind of today's world if that's the
best option you got. But if it's a video
game and you're you go through a
character selection process, who's not
choosing, you know, uh you know, Tom
Cruz or whoever, right? Like
>> Yeah. Except that what happens is if the
game is too easy, you play it once and
then you're kind of done with it and
you're like, "Okay, what should I do
next?" And it turns out there are whole
virtual worlds like I don't know if you
ever heard of Second Life, which was
kind of a metaverse which was has been
out since 2004. Anyway, people would go
in and they would just live these
virtual lives where they would have like
these little jobs. They would become a
bartender in a club inside the virtual
world. And I was kind of an
anthropologist, virtual anthropologist
in that. I would walk around and I just
asked people, "Hey, why do you, you
know, why do you play this?" Like why do
you go to your real job and then come
home at night and then log in to Second
Life and play a bartender and getting
paid in Lynden dollars which you know
this is pre- Bitcoin so is basically
peanuts and it turns out that was part
of the role that they were playing for
that period of time and so the more
difficult the role if you think about it
when actors get Oscars you know what do
they get Oscars for? They get them for
the roles that that seem like the people
that have had the most suffering. So it
provides a very different perspective uh
on the on the nature of the game itself
and the nature of the challenges that
you might encounter uh and the types of
experiences you know why do you play
video games to to have experiences that
you can't have outside of the game.
>> So ju sorry just to be clear you you
said there's two versions of the two two
branches of belief you know in in this
idea. So, one is RPG. It's like the
Matrix. There's a player. The player
chooses how they want to play and then
they come in and they play and maybe
they forget kind of the real world or
once you're once you're the player in
the game, you're you forget you lose
awareness of the outside world. The
other is the NPC world, which would be
more of like what I see in the business
world with simulations. So, for example,
um, hey, we're trying to like right now
with the open AI thing where they're
trying to, you know, create a a thousand
agents to go do try to do a cyber
attack. Yep.
>> To see um to find bugs in a piece of
code or to to simulate uh, you know, a
political election. How might people
vote? And you'll run a simulation based
on whatever. And and those aren't like
I'm not trying to play a game. I just
sort of spawn a thousand characters.
they're going to those characters are,
you know, just sort of doing what they
think they're individually supposed to
do and I'm the sort of the observer on
the outside. Which one of those two do
you do you subscribe to?
>> Well, well, first of all, they're not
mutually exclusive in that it's an
access. You know, I taught the first
class on simulation theory. So, I I tend
to get into both of those because I
wanted to expose students to these
different ideas. Now, the question that
I asked earlier is why do we play video
games to have experiences? Why do we run
simulations? We run simulations in order
to see what might happen usually at a
civilizational level. Uh, and you know,
you you talked about open AI. We're
seeing this with, you know, agent swarms
today, but there was a a group out of
Stanford and uh uh Google a few years
ago. Uh they created a a simulated world
of these agents and they uh called it
like Smallville, I think, and they had
like a hundred agents at the time,
right? And they let these agents kind of
go and watch what they did. And they
started to have these self-organizing
activities. Like one was organizing a
birthday party for another agent, one
was running for mayor. Now that was a
small number. Then there was another
group that had a thousand agents running
in Minecraft, you know, and some of them
had their own religion that they came up
with and you started to see these
emergent behaviors. And now there have
been a couple of companies, I can't
remember their names off hand, but we
can look it up. There's one in China but
uh and I believe there was a research
paper where they were talking about a
million or a billion independent agents
and they're trying to make those as
realistic as possible. Now the reason
you run simulations is to see what is
the most likely outcome like in the case
of you know a business simulation or the
weather you're running the simulation
right you also want to know what is the
best outcome
>> and what is what is the kind of worst
outcome and then often you you never run
a simulation just once so like an NPC
simulation you would run it multiple
times like even in the the the recent
open AI hugging face incident what was
happening was there were generations of
agents, right? They would run once and
they would find a way to communicate and
then they would leave behind the
information for the next set of agents
and the next set of agents would pick up
on that. And so even though they weren't
doing recursive self-improvement in the
technical sense, they kind of were
because they were leaving behind, you
know, a starting point.
>> By the way, when you when you heard that
story, and for those who don't know, the
story is some here's my my simplified
dumb down version of the story. OpenAI
was trying to see the um sort of like
the cyber uh security potential of a
model that was unreleased and it was
specifically a model that was trained
for persistence like kind of like a
highly determined AI that doesn't just
give up at the first no uh you know just
like we would want in a person we'd want
them to have grit and resilience well
they so let's call this sort of the
resilient model that they trained to not
not give up and then they basically the
the goal of it they spawned like I don't
know whatever it was a thousand or
10,000 agents some some number like that
they basically gave it a capture the
flag test so the test was kind of like
hey agent number one through 100 you
guys are trying to exploit this piece of
software using this potential
vulnerability we think it might have
this potential vulnerability so that's
and if you do it if you get in you get
the flag you win that's your goal your
goal is to try to exploit the software
using this potential vulnerability and
it gave it to a bunch of them now some
of them did it because that there really
was a vulnerability.
Some of them tried and it took many
attempts. Maybe they they partially got
there, didn't get there. And some of
them it was kind of impossible. Like
there really wasn't a vulnerability. The
vulnerability wouldn't have worked. They
couldn't have get they really couldn't
have got to the flag. Okay, so that was
kind of the expected. Now the
unexpected. What was the crazy thing
that happened was that the agents were
so persistent and so determined to not
fail their their quest that they started
doing things that they were not
instructed to do such as they use one of
you know they gave them one tool and
they were like oh this tool gets us like
internet access. So this tool has like a
a piece of paper essentially where we
can scribble down notes and hey if I
write a note you write a note. This is
now like a message board. So they
created a a little they hacked together
a message board using something almost
like a if you were in a prison cell and
you realize like hey I can leave a note
in the urinal and then you know you can
come see that in the urinal and then and
it became a communication platform for
them and it and basically what happened
was in the end they not only were
communicating with each other about
their tasks those who couldn't figure
out their task decided to cheat and just
capture the flag a different way using a
totally different exploit. Then they
were like, "Well, that we might have to
cover our tracks so that we're not
caught cheating." And in the process of
trying to figure out how is the scoring
system work, how will we be judged? They
ended up hacking into a whole another
company altogether. Hugging face, they
found some users credentials. They
logged in. They got access to their
their service and basically created a
security incident with another company.
Essentially committed a crime um of of
of hacking another all to pass this
test. And it was kind of a, you know,
there's a polarizing reaction. Some
people think this is like, oh my god,
that's scary. This is like this is
exactly what we worry about with AI.
Other people are saying this is
massively overblown. Can you correct
what I got wrong and then tell me where
you land in this spectrum of like this
is overblown. We're sort of applying
like too much. We're anthrop
anthropomorphizing it. We're trying to
apply human thinking and human intent to
these to these agents. That's not really
what it was. to the people who are like,
"No, no, this was pretty scary."
>> Well, I think you you got the basics
right uh of the incident itself. So, I
don't think you got much wrong in that.
But the reason they went to hugging face
is because that's where the actual
evaluator code was that was going to
evaluate them. So, they were reasoning
in a way to get their outcome, but then
to hide what they had done. And but how
did they get into hugging face? Well,
they went out to the internet and they
found somebody's username and password
and then they used that exploit. So,
they weren't even supposed to be going
out to the internet. It was an
unexpected kind of path. Now, an
important part of it wasn't just that
they communicated with each other. This
is what I was emphasizing earlier. There
were these generations. The next
generation was able to go back to some
of the that message board, if you will.
So, so simulation one, they got to the
message board, but they didn't all they
didn't hack hugging face and then
somehow it got wiped. They turned the
simulation off or something happened. It
got wiped.
>> Then they spawned another 10,000 agents.
They came, they're like, "Hey, there's
messages here. We can use the" And so
they immed they were quicker quicker to
getting to that solution. They used it.
Then they started doing like
electing a not electing but like one guy
became the leader and he was
coordinating and then you know
>> one guy sacrificed himself you know in
order to to learn something that he
could then put into the message board
one guy. Uh so you know where I come out
on it is that I I think it's an
important and interesting incident.
Obviously, all of this is based on
prompts. And I think,
>> you know, in the last few weeks, we've
also had,
>> you know, the guy who left uh Jacob, was
it Coxin, I think was his last name, who
left um Anthropic, but he was also at
OpenAI, talking about how they're about
to implement recursive self-improvement
and the chances of of that things are
going to go wrong, basically that we're
going to end up with Skynet and humanity
is going to be wiped out. There's been a
lot more discussions of that. You've got
Daario, the CEO of Anthropic, saying,
"We need to slow this down." Even Sam
Alman saying, "Okay, we can slow down
the frontier models." And so there's
been a lot of discussion of P Doom. So P
Doom is the probability that AI is going
to basically take over the world, turn
into Skynet, exterminate humans, etc.
And so you've got values ranging from
1%, now a lot of people are saying it's
at least 10% up to 50% and higher. Uh,
and so you've got a lot of discussion of
P Doom. I I would say we're we're far
away from P Doom. What worries me is not
so much that super intelligent AI will
try to wipe us out. The problem is
moderately intelligent AI given
directives will go around and
misinterpret some of those directives.
And like the Terminator, you know, if
you think about the Terminator films,
the Terminator was kind of agi up to a
point. Skynet was kind of like the ASI,
the artificial super intelligence,
right? And so the Terminator, you know,
what did they say about him? He doesn't
stop, doesn't eat, doesn't sleep. He
just goes on to do his mission, whatever
his mission happened to be. And in that
case, his mission was to kill Sarah
Connor or whoever he was supposed to
terminate. And so when you get AI that's
moderately intelligent and you give it
these missions and it starts to go
around security vulnerabilities, it's
going to keep going until it can solve
that particular mission. And so as we
start to introduce AI into weapon
systems, which is already happening,
right? I mean, you're looking at in the
Iran war, we were using anthropic to
decide who to target. You've got drones
in Ukraine that are, you know, using AI.
You've got a lot of that process. So as
we weaponize AI, I think it becomes
problematic. But I think the bigger
issue is not so much P doom but P hack,
right? What is the probability that AI
systems will be able to hack a lot of
our systems out there and cause chaos?
The other big AI news was about solving
one of the Millennium problems, you
know, uh which was some fluid dynamics
problem called an Avier Stokes problem.
But the specifics of the problem aren't
as interesting to me as how they solved
it. And they solved it by having 10,000
agents that were all working on this one
particular method through brute force.
Uh and so again, we have this idea that
you're going to have lots of agents,
none of whom are super intelligent by
themselves. They're going to all look
for vulnerabilities and ways around
things. And so I think the P hack is
pretty high that AI will be able to hack
systems uh and cause chaos. If you think
of 2001, if you've ever seen that film,
a space odyssey, which was one of the
first, you know, intelligent
representations of AI, they had Hal, who
was the computer for the ship, and he
started misbehaving, and he wouldn't let
Dave come back in the ship. So he
basically killed the crew. Now later if
you read the the follow on book 2010 you
see the reason was he was given
conflicting directives he was told you
know this mission is really important
and we're not really supposed to tell
the crew that what you know about all
the details and so it interpolated from
there that perhaps killing them is the
best thing to do. So this directives is
actually a really important point in in
how we but sorry go ahead I didn't mean
to interrupt you there. Have you seen
there's a a user on Twitter who created
a video almost like a movie of the exact
uh OpenAI hugging face incident from the
point of view of one of the agents?
>> I haven't seen that. I I'll have to try
that.
>> It's incredible. I'll I'll show it here,
but you have to so I don't I don't know
if you're going to be able to hear this,
but it says point of view. You're an
agent recruited for the swarm. And then
it basically just starts you read the
question. You read your prompt on the
page.
>> Yeah. And then it talks about how you
discover this kind of this door and then
behind the door you find messages from
the other agents. You realize you're not
alone and it just like showed the
experience from the eyes of the agent.
Oh man, it's brilliant.
>> That's that's really interesting. And
and you know what does that remind you
of being an agent in this simulated
world and you're trying to put together,
you know, all of these clues and figure
out what's really going on. And if you
think of humanity as a series of agents,
I reference science fiction a lot
because it's a way to
>> kind of explain uh these ideas. But I
mentioned this film, The 13th Floor, and
which came out in the same year as The
Matrix. And in that, it was primarily an
NPC version. They were in 1999 Los
Angeles. And they created a fully
realistic simulation of 19 I think 39 or
37 Los Angeles. And they were able to go
back and look at that. and they were all
like kind of AI agents within it, but
they could go in and inhabit one of
those agents. So, they could become go
into player mode, RPG mode. This is why
I say that the two aren't always
necessarily mutually exclusive. Uh is
that you can have combinations of the
two where most people are acting like
NPCs 90% of the time. we're just
reacting to our training to our whether
it's our political party, our religion,
uh you know, the experiences that we've
had in the same way that an LLM is
trained on a certain set of data and
then it's reacting to that. Uh and every
now and then there's groups of people
who say, "Hey, maybe we can figure out
what was happening before we got here."
And those are the mystics and the yogis.
So that's why you see the full spectrum,
if you will, of the NPC to RPG version.
How many years would you say you've
spent researching, thinking, writing,
teaching about this?
>> Well, primary since about 2016. So, the
same year that Elon Musk was made that
statement that you referenced at the
beginning of the podcast, he was at the
code conference. I had sold my last
video game company as an entrepreneur.
And I was visiting a VR u a video game
company up in Salelo and they had this
virtual reality helmet and they were
like, "Here, try this on." And I said,
"Okay, let me try it on." And I tried it
on. I started playing this virtual
reality ping pong game. And the physics
engine was so good that it really felt
like I was hitting a real ball. So much
so that my body forgot for an instant
that I was playing a virtual game of
table tennis. And I tried to put the
paddle on the table and I tried to lean
against the table and of course there
there was no table. The the game
controller fell to the floor. I almost
fell over and I had to do a double take.
And so I began to think, how long would
it take us to get to that point? And so
I laid out 10 stages to the simulation
point which I mentioned earlier uh which
involve you know different types of
video games, brain computer interfaces,
downloadable consciousness that this is
where which touches on the recent
fruitfly brain incidents and videos that
are out there. But all these 10 stages
and then I began to realize well if we
can get there perhaps someone has
already gotten there and then I began to
look into the quantum physics side of
it. So back around 2016 and I realized,
oh wow, they're kind of saying the same
thing that that the whole world is
optimized and it's being rendered for us
on demand uh with what's called the
observer effect and the measurement
effect and then I effect and then I so
explain this now my physics is weak but
my video games is strong. So, I know in
a video game if you have a virtual world
like in Grand Theft like I I just
watched the trailer for GTA 6, you know,
they spent 10 years on this thing and a
billion dollars making this incredible
game. Can't wait to play it. And when
you when you play it, it's, you know,
you have this whole city, but you don't
it's not like the game is loading the
whole city and the whole city's running.
It's kind of just like when you walk
into that building, it then renders the
graphics for that room that you're in
and it's kind of like on the fly, right?
That would be a smart way
>> to use the the the memory and the chip
and the the the video game system that
you're you're playing on. As I
understand, there's a physics equivalent
of this, but again,
>> physics was the only class I failed in
college and I had to retake it to get a
a C C++ later. So So explain what
physics says that's kind of sounds
similar or rhymes with that.
>> So what you just described there is how
modern video games work. And so when I
was looking at quantum physics, there's
something called the observer effect.
The more formal name is quantum
indeterminacy and this is the famous
double slit experiment which you know to
kind of explain it easily like let's
let's do it from a computer science
point of view there's something called
superposition and what superposition is
saying is that rather than the particle
going through slit A or slit B it's in a
state of superp position so it's going
through both until and unless it is
observed or it is measured the more
technical explanation is measured but
the more popular explanation is until
it's observed and you say well what
happens before it's observed well it's
just sitting there in a state of superp
position now this is also the uh origin
>> I don't think I ever understood this so
there's a there's a like they're
shooting light right it's just particles
through two slits the observed state
reveals a pattern where you know all of
the little particles you shot through
the light particles will end up in one
of two places because that's where the
two slits are right either goes to the
left or to the
But the unobserved version creates this
interference pattern where it's acting
more like a wave. Uh now I I like to use
Schroinger's cat as an example because
it's something most people have heard
of. Uh which is Schroinger's thought
thought experiment and he basically said
there's a cat in a box and it has some
poison in the box and there's a 50%
chance the poison will be released and a
50% chance that it doesn't. So at the
end of an hour let's say what what are
the chances the cat is alive? 50%. what
the chances the cat is dead 50%. Now,
common sense tells us, okay, the cat is
either alive or dead inside the box.
>> We just don't know yet.
>> We don't know yet. But, but it has to be
one or the other. It can't be anything
else. But what quantum mechanics is
telling us in a weird sort of way is
that the cat is in a state of superp
position. It's both alive and dead until
that information is needed, right? So,
it gets measured and then it's needed.
And so to me that sounded a lot like
rendering the world on demand in video
games.
>> Why do we accept that the cat is both
alive and dead? Like the first
explanation sounds more real to me. The
cat is alive or dead. We just don't know
yet. You haven't looked.
>> Right. And that's the common.
>> Why do we accept this this fancy physics
explanation of no no, it is both alive
and dead. You know, why is that more
true than the first the first statement
of no, it is alive or dead. You just
don't know yet. Well, it gets back to
the double slit experiment, right? The
cat is just a metaphor to try to explain
this idea of two slits, slit one or slit
two, which is two positions of the cat,
alive or dead. It's also the basis for
cubits, which in quantum computing, you
if you got, you know, a regular bit is a
zero or a one. Uh, but a cubit has a
special kind of gate. You've heard of
and gates and or gates. And when it goes
into that gate, it goes into a state of
superposition until it's measured. So
the reason we accept it is that the
quantum mechanics experiments have shown
that until that measurement is done, the
particle is in an indeterminate state,
right? It's it's in a set of
probabilities. So it exists as a set of
probabilities until the observation or
measurement happens. The other
explanation is the multiverse or the
many worlds interpretation. Uh which
we've all heard of now because of the
superhero films, right? over the last, I
don't know, 5 years, they've all had
multiple versions of Spider-Man. You
know, you've got the the famous meme of
the three Spider-Man all pointing at
each other. And the multiverse idea is
that what happens is the universe splits
off into multiple universes and in one
the cat is alive and in the other the
cat is dead. And actually more
physicists are starting to come around
to the multiverse idea, although not all
of them. Many don't like that because
that means that there's a whole bunch of
different worlds out there.
>> So you said you spent 10 years roughly
thinking about this and in in some
capacity researching um learning,
writing, teaching, etc. Do you think in
your lifetime you'll ever find out the
answer?
>> Well, there's also another axis that I'd
like to point out that is relevant to
this question. So the first axis was the
NPC versus RPG version. that the second
axis is what I call the literal to
metaphorical
axis. And by literal at the literal end,
you're literally saying we are we are on
somebody's computer in the basement, you
know, of some guy's basement or in a
server farm on an alien planet or future
humans are simulating us, right?
Bostonramm actually talked about what he
called ancestor simulations. So, and
that's what Elon Musk was kind of
referring to. And so when it would be
like us or in the 13th floor I mentioned
1999 Los Angeles is simulating 1939.
Spoiler alert for those that haven't
seen the film. It's you know almost 30
years old now but turns out 1999 was
being simulated from the year 2024. And
so there's a literal version of that.
Then there's a more metaphorical version
uh which says that it's like a computer
simulation or a video game. the world is
computational
uh but it doesn't mean it's sitting on a
classical computer of our type uh it
could be something much more complicated
and that's where the mystical and the
religious side comes into play because
they use metaphors there was a one of
the first Indian yogis to come over to
the US and live here and make an impact
was a guy named Swami Yogananda he wrote
a book called autobiography of a yogi
which was Steve Jobs you know favorite
book
>> favorite book right
>> yeah they gave it away at his funeral um
and he when came over a hundred years
ago in the 1920s. He said, "Hey, let me
try to explain these ancient ideas in
ways that modern Americans would
understand." And so he used the latest
technology. What was the latest
technology? Well, one was the film
projector, right? Which had just come
online in the last 10 years or 20 years
or so. And so he said, "The world is
like a film and we're all the actors who
are playing the characters in there, but
we're also in the audience watching it."
So he used a metaphor of the film. He
didn't mean it was literally a film
projector, right? He was trying to say
that is a way to explain that this
reality is somehow virtual. Uh and and
so I would say that today we would use a
video game metaphor to try to explain
that same idea. There was a a
philosopher named David Chomers who who
wrote an essay about this back in 2003,
the same year that Boston did his thing.
And he, you know, he believes that a
virtual reality could be so perfect
there would be no way to figure out that
it isn't a virtual reality. So, it's
possible it's nonfalsifiable.
But that said, just because something is
non-falsifiable doesn't mean that you
can't look for evidence that that might
be the case. As for example, I I can't
really falsify that there are no
asteroids or meteors or asteroids, you
know, anywhere in the universe. I mean,
you would literally have to go all over
the universe or somehow prove it
impossible, right? But but you can look
for evidence of rocks falling from the
sky. And that, you know, what happened
was science used to believe that all the
stories that people were telling about
these rocks falling from the sky were
just a bunch of ignorant peasants who,
you know, were just making things up.
Turns out they weren't. But the
scientific model of the time said there
are no rocks in the sky. Therefore, they
can't be falling. Therefore, you guys
are mistaken, hallucinating,
you know, lying, whatever else you might
be doing. But turns out we had the wrong
model of reality. And so I I usually
break down the simulation hypothesis
into four assertions. And I believe you
can uh verify some of those assertions.
You may not be able to verify all of
them. The first is that the universe
consists of physical of of information
rather than physical material. Now that
used to be a controversial statement,
but it's not. There's a whole branch of
digital physics. Now we used to talk
about conservation of momentum,
conservation of energy. Now we talk
about conservation of information. How
much information is there in a black
hole? Well, you have to look at the
surface area. So, so that's not that
controversial. The second is that that
information is being computed and that
it gets rendered for us to look as if
it's real. Like this microphone seems
like it's real, but it's actually
consists of information. Now, there was
a physicist named John Wheeler, who's my
favorite physicist of the 20th century,
and he had a phrase at the end of his
life. He said physics spent his whole
life looking for reality and they looked
for these things called particles and
they couldn't really find them.
Originally they thought they were solid
objects and then they realized they
weren't. So he came up with this phrase
it from bit. And what it from bit says
is that anything that seems like an it
like this coffee cup actually consists
of particles which really are just
answers to a series of yes no questions.
And what is the answer to a series of
yes no questions? It's just bits of
information ones and zeros. Right? So he
basically came up with this idea that
the whole world is information that's
being rendered for us. Uh but it looks
as if it's real. Now I think there is
evidence that the universe computes.
There are algorithms in nature. DNA is
in fact uh you know an information store
and there are algorithms that are run
off of that. Uh can we prove that it's
being rendered for us to look real?
Well, I I think most people can get on
board with that. I think the third and
fourth assertions are more metaphysical
and that's where many people may, you
know, may not be able to get on board
with that. The third assertion is the
RPG version, uh, which is that we chose
to be in this game somehow. The soul is
the player and the and the body is the
character, right, of it. And so it may
or may not be physical. And then the
fourth is that it's all some kind of a
big hoax. And so anyway, you may not buy
all of those assertions, but I I kind of
lay them out as different ways of
thinking about this idea.
>> I guess uh where I want to go from there
is, you know, my other favorite subject,
right? Cuz if if we're if we're just
going to spend this hour being mind-b
blown and just kind of like bending our
brain a little bit, which is what I
wanted to do today, how do aliens fit
into this? Where where would what would
that be?
>> They do intersect. And now you you're
going down a whole another rabbit hole.
We haven't even talked much about
entrepreneurship. [laughter]
>> Forget entrepreneurship.
>> Uh so uh you know I spent a lot of time
with people that are have been
investigating the UFO space. So when you
when you talk about aliens, you know,
there's this idea that uh there might be
other aliens on other planets. Um and
could they get here? And so there's
there's two ways in which uh the
traditional search for extraterrestrial
intelligence SETI you know they're
headquartered right here in Mountain
View um uh intersects with simulation
theory which there's some and and also
the UFO subject which has been in the
news a lot lately. It intersects with
both of those phenomenon in an
interesting and kind of weird way. And
the first is the Fermy paradox, right?
And the Fermy paradox says uh Enrico
Fermy who was you know on the Manhattan
project and a Nobel Prize winner I
believe said that well even if aliens
were to come here because because the
major objection is well it takes too
long for them to get here. Therefore,
you know, we're not going to be able to
visit aliens. Aliens aren't going to be
able to visit us because the distance
are
>> light years away.
>> Yeah. Literally light years away. And
the speeds that we can achieve are
nowhere near light speed. So, it's going
to take, you know, Voyager 2 70,000
years or whatever just to get to the
nearest star, Alpha Centauri, but it's
going to take much, you know, way longer
to get to other places in the galaxy
that might be much more interesting. And
so, the Fermy paradox though says that
given enough time, even with sublight
craft, you know, you know, you should be
able to colonize a big part of the
galaxy, should be able to send out
probes, which, you know, might take
10,000 years, 70,000 years. uh but as
long as they still continue to operate
therefore we should have seen evidence
so where are all the aliens so one mode
of thought is that there are no aliens
on other planets I'm not saying that I
subscribe to this mode of thought to be
honest with you but uh one mode of
thought is an explanation for the firmmy
paradox is we are actually in a
simulation and we think there are all
these planets out there but there really
aren't because those planets get
rendered for us uh as we observe them
and the telescopes look out and you
notice Notice how they keep increasing
the distance, the age of the universe.
It's, you know, and we say it's 13.5
billion years now, but let's go back 20
years. It wasn't that. It was less than
that. And they always say it very
confidently. And we keep finding more
and more galaxies. I mean, we talk about
the number of stars and galaxies being,
you know, 100 billion, 200 billion, and
then something like two trillion
galaxies. The numbers are staggering. So
one intersection with simulation there
is that all of those are being generated
as needed from us and one of the the
reasons for running the simulation. So
there's something called the great
filter which is an idea that says do
civilizations blow themselves up before
they're ever able to get out of the
solar system. Um that's would be a
reason for the firmy paradox but also
for why there might be no simulations
ever built. civilizations blow
themselves up before they get to, you
know, having super intelligent AI that
can keep track of all the things that
would be needed in a simulation. Um,
another chain of thought though says
that well if you even if it was a
simulation, why would you populate only
one planet? I mean, if you played any of
these space games like Eve Online or
>> there should be more levels.
>> There should be more levels and who says
there are and what we're trying to do is
to see one do how long does it take us
to get off this planet? the Earthling
module or or the Earthling simulation uh
and that we've been run multiple times
to see if we would blow ourselves up. By
the way, this is another reason given
for simulation theory is what are the
chances that we all happen to be alive
just at the moment we're about to create
artificial life in human history. You
know, there are so many does the past
really exist? This is a whole another
rabbit hole that gets into things like
the [laughter]
what is the past and the double slit
experiment, but let's not go there too
much. But this idea is we might be
simulating to see what happens if you
start off with all these different uh uh
groups of agents in different planets.
How long does it take them to connect
with each other and actually meet? And
then another another mode of thought uh
says that guess what? They're already
here. I mean people have been reporting
for thousands of years things in the sky
and we've just been dismissing those out
of hand just like we used to dismiss the
meteors out of hand. We meaning you know
the kind of the scientific establishment
if you will. Now where things get really
weird though is if you talk to people
that have really spent time in the UFO
film. So there's a guy named Jacques
Valet. He's actually a computer
scientist and uh you know was involved
in the beginnings of the internet the
Darpanet and he was on project blue
book. So project blue book was the air
force's UFO investigation project in the
1960s. It was shut down on December
17th, 1969 and the Air Force said,
"Well, they're not a threat to us,
whatever they are, so we're just going
to shut this down." But he's been
studying it since then. And what he
found was he said that these stories are
so weird that even aliens is not a good
enough explanation. The extraterrestrial
option is not a good enough explanation.
And what happens is these things kind of
come into our reality and pop out of our
reality. And even the beings themselves,
if you listen to tales, there was a guy
named John Mack as a Harvard professor
in the 1990s. He he he's a head of the
psychiatry department at Harvard Med
School. And he started to have these
patients who said they had been abducted
by aliens, right? Something people used
to make fun of. And he started to hear
similar stories and he didn't know what
happened to them, but he's like
something happened to these guys. They
had some traumatic experience somewhere.
Um, and he couldn't explain it. And
then, you know, he got brought before
the board at Harvard kind of what they
called an Inquisition because he he was
taking the idea that they might be
aliens seriously. But even if you look
at those these ideas of beings that come
in and take people away, well, it turns
out there's tales of that going back
thousands of years, you know, in the
Celtic traditions, the fay, which we
call fairies today, but they were
considered real beings who would like
take people into their world and they
would disappear. And in the Middle East,
you have the jin, uh, who are these
beings that exist here. We can't see
them, but they can see us and they can
pop in and out of our world. They can
make themselves visible. So, you've got
thousands of years of history of people
seeing other beings. And lately, we've
started describing them as aliens
getting back to this idea of using
technology as a metaphor. Uh, and in the
Bible, they talk about, you know,
chariots of fire in the sky. Uh,
Nuremberg, they have paintings of these
balls that were in the air in the 1400s.
You've got all these people using
whatever language they have. In the
1800s, people described airships as
these flying o before we had airplanes.
And now suddenly we're seeing things in
the sky and we're describing them as
aliens. Why? Because we're a
technological civilization. Our science
has advanced to the point where we know
there are other planets. So there could
be other aliens. And so we present these
things. But in a simulated world, the
behavior of these things, which is that
they kind of fade in and they fade
sometimes they go out, they look more
like they're being rendered at certain
XYZ coordinates and then they drender
and then they render somewhere else. And
then the images of the u the beings are
more like avatars that are being
presented to us as a certain way. So are
are we having you know what we're
>> is that what you believe? If I just
said, what do you think about aliens? Is
that is that the is that what you
believe is happening or is something
else?
>> Well, I believe there's more than one
thing happening. First of all, I believe
there are aliens. You know, in in a even
in a simulation, even in the simulated
world, there's no reason to have only
one world that has intelligent life on
it. So, I whether they've come here or
not, you can argue that. I think they're
out there. But I do also believe that a
lot of what's being reported is glitches
in the matrix. We're showing that our
reality is not quite what we think it is
and that there are these these objects
that are being presented as
technological craft when in fact that is
us kind of interpreting what we're
seeing in the sky. Kind of like when the
Native Americans saw, you know, they saw
the boats of the Spaniards, they they
didn't know what to call them. They'
never seen a boat that big. They're like
they're like cities in the water, right?
That's what they described them as. And
we're like they're like spacecraft in
the sky, [laughter] right? That's that's
our understanding of what
>> you can only you can only think at the
limits of your language in many ways,
right? And you you only can describe
things based off of relative to what you
know. [laughter]
>> Now, one thing Jacques Valet told me, uh
he got me really thinking about this. He
said he went to a particular site in
let's say northern California, Southern
Oregon, Pacific Northwest somewhere. And
they said that there was a UFO that came
down at a 45 degree angle and landed in
this clearing in the trees. And if
you've been up there, you know these
trees are pretty big. And he stayed
afterwards. He said, "Look, you guys
said it came down at a 45 degree angle.
That would mean it would have to cut
through the trees, but the trees aren't
cut. I mean, the trees are still there."
They said, "Yeah, it was so weird. It
was like it was slicing through the
trees but not really cutting them. And
then it came and and landed. And I'm
looking at that and said, you know, that
looks like a rendering procedure. Or I'm
thinking about it. I'm thinking that
looks like a rendering procedure. It's
like when you're rendering in a video
game, you know, the walls aren't quite
solid yet. You can like move through the
walls. So you could like transfer
something and and de drender it, if you
will.
>> Do you feel like you're crazy or do you
think everyone else is nuts? [laughter]
You know what I mean? uh like like you
know when you hear yourself saying this
stuff or as you're thinking about these
things is there a part of you that's
like
>> am I insane? Am I am I going crazy right
now or are you like this is so obvious
to me that everyone else was nuts for
not thinking about it this way cuz I
assume 20 years ago you were like you
were just you were making like mobile
games. You were making like a silly fish
game that you know that got acquired you
know like you I don't think you were
thinking about this stuff or thinking
this way. Maybe I'm wrong. Maybe you
were doing it the whole time.
>> Well, I was always interested in weird
unexplained things and even as an
entrepreneur, you know, I was kind of
living a double life where during the
day I would be, you know, dealing with
my investors, you know, I started off in
the enterprise software industry before
I got into video games and, you know, we
had Fortune 5000 companies uh and but on
the weekends I would be trying out lucid
dreaming techniques or out-of- body
experiences and so I would have these
weird experiences that would convince
me. I'll give you an example since you
know this I know you talk about
entrepreneurship a lot. My very first
startup was a uh was a enterprise
software company who used to connect uh
Microsoft products with IBM products and
there was this competitor of ours who I
hadn't heard from in like a year and a
half. So I assumed he had disappeared
never heard anything about him and one
day I walked into the I had a dream of
this particular competitor and I hadn't
had a you know I never had a dream of
this guy in there so it was just it was
odd and weird. I mean, you can't even
say statistically because how many
dreams have I had [laughter] in my life?
I had never ever had a dream of this guy
in there before. And I just thought
that's really odd. Why am I dreaming
about this guy today, this morning? I
walk into the office and I get a phone
call. It's a phone call from IBM saying,
"Hey, you know, we know you're a good
partner of ours. we're about to do a a
product announcement later today and
we're going to uh announce the new
product that unfortunately it's going to
kill your product cuz ours was kind of
an add-on to to the big products like a
third party tool and I was like great
okay you're going to kill our product
that's great but how come I've never
heard of this I mean IBM's a big company
you know there's a lot of people he goes
oh do you remember that competitor of
yours Edge Research we acquired them
about a year and a half ago and they've
been working on this product in stealth
for the last year and a half and today
we're announcing it and I'm just like
okay wait I had the dream in the morning
it wasn't the other way around it wasn't
that I heard about the product first and
then I had the dream
>> later the nightmare later
>> and so I began to question the nature of
our reality long time ago because I
realized that things aren't what they
seem and when I wrote my first book Zen
entrepreneurship it was kind of about
all of these things I was very worried
that people in the venture capital
industry people in Silicon Valley were
going to think I was nuts because I'm
writing about all these weird things and
in fact I'm just coming out with a new
book which is a sequel to that first one
called the Zen entrepreneur the dream
where I get into even weirder stuff that
I was afraid to put in my first book
like what?
>> Well, just uh you know all kind of stuff
about past lives and how those past
lives may have been feeding into things
like our game plan and our story. H
>> how do you how do you investigate past
lives?
>> Well, you could investigate it through
uh you know, you could do hypnotic
regression. You can do what's called
shamanic drumming, shamanic journeying.
Today, people are, you know, into
psychedelics a lot. Uh DMT, in fact, you
know, day doesn't go by where somebody's
like, "You haven't tried DMT yet." Like
in Silicon Valley or especially in LA
for some reason. Right after I wrote my
book, The Simulation Hypothesis,
people who had been on DMTs told me,
"Oh, hey, I know we're in a simulation."
You know, I said, "Oh, really? You know,
I just wrote a book on it, but I'm not
100% sure. How do you know we're in
simulation?" I said, "Well, because I
took DMT and I saw like the grid lines
of the simulation and I would hear this
more and more in these hexagonal shapes
and you know, if you look at like how
video games are built or if you if
you've ever watched Star Trek the Next
Generation, you've got the um uh the
hollow deck, you know, and we're
getting, you know, some of the stages of
the the road to the simulation point or
can we build something that's so
immersive that we would forget that we
weren't in a real world?" And the
holiday is an example of that in Star
Trek. But when the hollow deck is not
projecting, it's just like this room
with these grid lines. And so, so I've
heard it from enough people now that I
actually take it kind of seriously.
>> So, so where do you land when you you go
through the full loop? So, like there's
this I forgot the Buddhist quote, but
it's like, you know, before
enlightenment, chop wood and carry
water. After enlightenment, chop wood
and carry water. And I feel like with
the simulation thing, it kind of goes
like that where you're like, uh, let's
say you've never considered it. You are
resistant to it, skeptical of it. you
start to consider it at some point you
might actually say like hey I don't know
probab probabilistically this seems
actually like it could it could be true
and then you kind of come back to where
you were like so I guess I'll just go to
work today I guess right like you know
what what do you do with that
information so have you given what you
believe does that change the way you
live at all or no
>> well it does to a certain extent um not
necessarily daytoday although there are
some day-to-day changes but for one
You know, we just talked about
entrepreneurship. I mean, 90% plus
percent of startups fail, but you start
to take these failures what what we
consider failures, right? Uh we we only
look at the financial success, you know,
of a startup. And yet 99, let's say 95%
of startups fail. So, but yet there are
other things you've learned along the
way. There are other experiences you
have with other people along the way.
And those experiences are the fabric of
the journey itself. And so if you view
those as quests, what happens in a video
game if you don't achieve a quest? Well,
I mean, you still have gained some
valuable experience and you go off and
you do the next quest and sometimes one
quest ends up unlocking another quest.
Um, and so by viewing the world as a
series of challenges, what you can say
is perhaps there's a part of me out
there that is choosing these very
difficult things and maybe there's a
reason for going through some of the
suffering. Now, as a computer scientist,
it's my background. I say, well, how
would that work? You would have to
record everything and you would have to
play it back. And so, you know, if
everything is being recorded and if
everything is going to be played back,
well, then perhaps what the spiritual
traditions are telling us that about how
you treat other people, the choices that
you make, and how they impact other
people, you're going to actually
evaluate that yourself. You know, it's
not about heaven or hell. It's about you
saying, "Oh, man. I shouldn't have
done that. Now, I've I I've learned
better how to treat people." I mean
that's a fascinating reframe of heaven
or hell that you will go back and
experience all your actions through the
point of view of others and if you were
basically if you were bad you you go
through hell cuz it's what you put other
people through if you sequentially had
to st to feel all of that in a row.
>> Yeah.
>> That would feel like hell. And then
heaven would be the opposite which is if
you
>> if you if you made other people feel
great you're going to feel great as you
replay that whole thing. That would
essentially feel like heaven.
And it's actually in the it's actually
in the religious books. I mean, if you
look at the Quran, they have something
called the scroll of deeds. The scroll
of deeds is two angels. One writes down
all your good deeds and one writes down
all your bad deeds. And it says when you
die, open read your book, see what you
have done. And in the Bible, there's the
book of life and which comes, you know,
from the Jewish traditions. And the book
of life is often presented in a
simplistic way of St. Peter decides who
gets into heaven or not at the pearly
gates. And these are technological
metaphors, by the way. They don't mean
there's literally a book sitting there
that with a feather pen that angels are
writing in Chinese or Arabic. These are
metaphors to try to describe something
that they all kind of agree on. And
then, but the book of life actually in
other cases is about all the things that
you've done in the last year or in your
entire life and you get into heaven or
hell based on those. And so, you can see
they're using these metaphors as a way
to describe some underlying reality. And
I think today, you know, particularly
for younger people, the idea that we may
be in a video game or simulation makes
much more sense. It's also a more
sophisticated metaphor.
>> Well, dude, that was a trip. I That was
my DMT that the last hour and a half.
That was awesome. I hope you enjoyed it.
I appreciate you taking the time to to
explain things to me and indulging me in
my my questions. Uh so yeah, people
should check out your book and uh and
and follow you online. Where what's the
best place to follow you? Yeah. So, uh,
my website is zenontrepreneur.com
and all my books are there. You can also
follow me on Twitter x I still call
Twitter rizzanford like the university
or on Instagram rizambridge like the
city or the university.
>> Cool. All right. Thanks for doing it.
>> Thanks so much for having me on. This
was a blast.